George Heinold Papers
© 2002 University of Connecticut
George Heinold Papers.
undated, 1916-1982.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Heinold, George.
7.25 linear feet.
George W. Heinold, lifelong resident of Madison, Connecticut, was an author on outdoor life and fishing who wrote extensively on his experiences primarily along the Connecticut shoreline. He published regularly in such periodicals as Outdoor Life, Field and Stream, and Readers' Digest.
MSS19980204
Biography
A lifelong resident of Madison, Connecticut, George W. Heinold ( 1916-1982 ) ranked as a leading writer of outdoor articles about animals, fishing, and hunting. Heinold served his community as a full time policeman. He also built a literary career by infusing his work with personal anecdotes, almost all of which occurred in the shoreline area of Madison, Clinton, and Killingworth before suburbanization changed the character of this region. In so doing, Heinold captured moments in the social history of the Connecticut shoreline for posterity. Moreover, he supported his articles with many photographs that he himself took and which also offer glimpses into life along the shore during Heinold's lifetime. As a professional writer, he won public recognition first in 1944 when voted as author of one of the year's best stories. He thereafter published many stories in Readers' Digest and anthologies that RD produced. He contributed regularly to such popular outdoor sports journals as Outdoor Life, Field and Stream, Sports Afield, True, and Ford (Motor Company) Times. In Outdoor Life, Heinold had his own department entitled "Salt Water" which appeared monthly.
Scope and Content
This collection chronicles the literary and photographic career of George W. Heinold, a native of Madison, Connecticut and writer of popular stories about outdoor life, fishing, and hunting. The papers cover the years from Heinold's birth in 1916 until his 1982 death. The bulk of the collection spans the fifteen-year period from 1965 until 1980 when Heinold enjoyed the peak of his fame and apparently produced his largest volume of output. The papers encompass his personal correspondence, including letters and related materials on his Madison property which the State commandeered for highway development in the 1950s and financial records, in addition to the published articles, unpublished manuscripts, and photographs-plus negatives thereof-that constitutes the main part of the papers. As well, the collection includes two newspaper articles written about Heinold, which appear at the end of Series III.
As a whole, the papers afford insights into the social history of the Connecticut shoreline between 1920 and 1982 from the perspective of the writer, who incorporated firsthand experiences into his prose and accompanying photographs. Beyond this attribute, the collection illustrates important aspects of male gender that constitute the persona of the American outdoor-and-sportsman of the mid-twentieth century. Heinold constructs a rugged version of masculinity that appealed to popular audiences throughout America. His accounts of his own experiences reveal the biases and decidedly male homosociability which collectively defined outdoor sports and leisure in the United States during the twentieth century.
Organization
Series I: Correspondence (1955-1981) includes all correspondence that did not accompany the articles and manuscripts of Series II. (This latter body can be found with Series II contents). In addition, the series contains letters and related materials on Heinold's Madison (Ct.) property which he lost to highway development during the mid-1950s. The loss of this land-claimed as eminent domain by the State of Connecticut-weighed on Heinold's mind until the end of the life. In the 1970s, he wrote an unpublished account of his battle with the state over this property entitled "Auf Wiedersehen, Little Walden." This manuscript appears in Series III in File 114.
Series II: Financial Materials (1916-1971) unites the few sparse financial materials that the collection contains. The series includes information on Heinold's savings account, sample tax returns, and bills that Heinold incurred on an assignment for Popular Science.
Series III: Articles and Manuscripts (1942-1982) comprises articles and manuscripts that constitute the main body of the collection, including any correspondence regarding submission or editing. Mostly typescript materials-although published versions are included, the series breaks down into several subseries. Subseries A: Dated articles and manuscripts; Subseries B: Undated materials in alphabetical order; Subseries C: Pieces written for "Salt Water" and Heinold's regular department in the periodical Outdoor Life; and, Subseries D: Articles written about Heinold. Each article/manuscript is listed by formal title if in quotes. If no formal title exists, the piece bears the subject title as identified by Heinold himself. In the absence of either a formal or subject title, the piece has a designation of "Untitled."
Dates for Subseries A reflect a variety of sources. If published, the article appears with the corresponding date of publication. In manuscript form, respective pieces bear either the date when Heinold sent out the item for consideration, or the last date appearing in any related correspondence. Those materials with a "circa" designation reflect undated items that appeared amid other manuscripts, all of which conclusively bore a similar date that now follows the "circa." All other manuscripts and articles are listed as undated in Subseries B.
The researcher should treat the first two subseries as intermingled. Heinold often wrote multiple drafts of articles under the same title, sometimes over the space of months and years, resubmitting them for publication accordingly. When dated, these manuscripts and articles appear in the first subseries, in the second if not. Therefore, the researcher should consult both subseries to insure a comprehensive history of any one piece. Similarly, the researcher should not necessarily treat any one dated article as a single occurrence in Subseries A. Rather, the researcher should look for successive or previous versions of the article or manuscript in question throughout the subseries to see the possible evolution of that piece.
The researcher should also be sure to check Series IV, which contains photographs for articles as well as subject and dated photographs that can relate to specific topics about which Heinold writes.
Series IV: Photographs (ca. 1955-1979) encompasses all photographs and negatives in the collection. Arrangement is again in subseries. Subseries A: Heinold family photographs; Subseries B: Dated photographs; Subseries C: Subject photographs; Subseries D: Printed, or published, photographs; Subseries E: Press photographs not by Heinold; and, Subseries F: Negatives for the Heinold-generated photographs of Subseries A-D. Negative arrangement corresponds exactly these subdivisions. However, not all photographs had accompanying negatives, and vice versa as well. Of special note are subject files for bluefish and stripers. In unprocessed form, Heinold's photographs of these fishes constituted roughly one-half of all pictures, with bluefish as the overwhelming majority. The two groups of photographs thus impeded proper and logical processing, which aimed for a proportionate representation. Therefore, the processor included only a sample of this material in the finalized collection. He first separated the photographs from the larger body of materials and then removed duplicate or similar images, reducing the mass to their present form and in proper proportion to one another.
Related Material
Archives and Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to literature and natural history. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
Marsh, Irving T. and Edward Ehre. Best Short Stories of 1944, New York, 1944.
Outdoor Life. Bound. January-June 1975.
. Marvels & Mysteries of Our Anima Word: A Family Guide to the Fascinating Creatures of the Earth, Sea, and Sky. New York: Reader's Digest, 1964.
Bibliography
George Heinold is the author of the articles listed below.
"Born Shrewd." Fawcett's Hunting Journal, ( 1975 ) 1: 40-42.
"Burglar from the Woods (RACOON). In Marvels & Mysteries of Our Anima Word: A Family Guide to the Fascinating Creatures of the Earth, Sea, and Sky. Reader Digest, 1964.
"Knights of the Deep Swamp (Wild Turkeys)." Yankee, ( November 1977 ): 116-20.
"The Porcupine: Knight of Many Spears." Yankee,, ( September 1976 ): 78-81.
"That Old Grey Fox (A nature study)." Yankee,, ( September 1977 ): 114-117.
"An Old Man Told Me." Marsh, Irving T. and Edward Ehre. Best Short Stories of 1944. 1944.
"Salt Water." Outdoor Life, Circa 1955-Circa 1975.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Places:
Madison (Conn.)--Newspapers, periodicals and journals.; Connecticut--Newspapers, periodicals, and journalism.; Connecticut--Recreation and sports.; Madison (Conn.)--Recreation and sports.
Subjects:
Outdoor Life (Periodical).; Journalism--Editing.; Fishing--United States.; Fishing--Connecticut.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.; Financial Records.; Press releases.; Manuscripts.; Typescripts.; Photocopies.
Occupations:
Author.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Heinold's son, Henry Robert Heinold, donated the papers to the University of Connecticut in the summer of 1982.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence, 1955-1981
  - Correspondence, 1955 Apr - 1959 Dec (Box 1:1)
  - Correspondence, 1960 Jan - 1969 Dec (Box 1:2)
  - Correspondence, 1970 Jan - 1974 Dec (Box 1:3)
  - Correspondence, 1975 Jan - 1981 Dec (Box 1:4)
  - Correspondence and Related Material on Heinold's Madison (CT) Property, 1956-1966 (Box 1:5)
- Series II: Financial Materials, 1916-1973
  - Financial Materials, 1916-1973 (Box 1:6)
- Series III: Articles and Manuscripts, 1944-1982
  - Subseries A: Dated Articles and Manuscripts, 1944-1982
    - "An Old Man Told Me," Outdoor Life, 1944 Jul (Box 2:7)
    - "I Settled for Stripers," Field and Stream, 1946 Jun (Box 2:8)
    - "One Striped Bass Mystery," Outdoor Life, 1948 May (Box 2:9)
    - "Poor Man's Salmon," True, 1949 May (Box 2:10)
    - "No Sport for Sissies," Saturday Evening Post, 1949 Aug 27 (Box 2:11)
    - "Blacks Are Brutes," Field and Stream, 1951 May (Box 2:12)
    - "Salt on Their Trails: The Days When the Bass Were Everywhere, 1956 Feb 25 (Box 2:13)
    - "Wahoo!," Outdoor Life, 1960 Apr (Box 2:14)
    - "Stripers North of the Border", 1967 Mar 7 (Box 2:15)
    - "Bombshell of the Brushlands", 1967 Mar 23 (Box 2:16)
    - "Mightiest Midget of Mining", 1967 Aug (Box 2:17)
    - "The People-Watching Fish", 1967 Sep (Box 2:18)
    - "The Crappie Is Also an Eastern Fish", 1967 Oct 17 - Nov 1 (Box 2:19)
    - "Fastest Flash in Fur", 1967 Nov 3 (Box 2:20)
    - Untitled, 1968 Mar 11 (Box 2:21)
    - "The Animal That Shoots Back", 1968 Apr 18 (Box 2:22)
    - "Nova Scotia's Striped 'Sea Barse'", 1968 Oct 5 (Box 2:23)
    - Untitled, 1968 Oct 11 (Box 2:24)
    - "Best Bets for Vacation Fishing", 1968 Nov 4 (Box 2:25)
    - Untitled, 1968 Nov 6 (Box 2:26)
    - "Changes in Fox Hunting", 1968 Dec 11 (Box 2:27)
    - "Frostbite Stripers", 1968 Dec 11 (Box 2:28)
    - "Connecticut Fishing", 1969 Jan 13 (Box 2:29)
    - "Rhode Island Fishing", 1969 Jan 13 (Box 2:30)
    - "Nature's Original Angler (Sold to Science Digest, 1969 Aug 14), 1969 Feb 17 (Box 2:31)
    - "Connecticut's Striper Revival", 1969 Mar 1 (Box 2:32)
    - "Bait for the Big Ones", 1969 Mar 16 (Box 2:33)
    - "Blitzes of Bluefish", 1969 Mar 22 (Box 2:34)
    - "We Are in Hot Water", 1969 Apr 3 - Aug 13 (Box 2:35)
    - "Bait for the Big Ones", 1969 Mar 26 (Box 2:36)
    - "By Golly, I've Got a Fish On!", 1969 May 27 (Box 2:37)
    - "Have You Seen This Plant", 1969 Jun 10 (Box 2:38)
    - "Fall Fishing in Rhode Island", 1969 Jun 11 (Box 2:39)
    - "Sultan of the Mountain Slopes", 1969 Jul 18 (Box 2:40)
    - "Connecticut", 1969 Aug 5 (Box 2:41)
    - "Winter Fishing in Connecticut", 1969 Oct 2 (Box 2:42)
    - "My Favorite Freshwater Fun-Fish", 1969 Oct 13 (Box 2:43)
    - "Konakees of Connecticut", 1969 Nov 5 (Box 2:44)
    - "Rhode Island and Connecticut", 1969 Nov 30 (Box 2:45)
    - "Newt: Our Changeable Aide", 1969 Dec 29 (Box 2:46)
    - "Connecticut", 1970 Jan 4 (Box 2:47)
    - "Rhode Island", 1970 Jan 4 (Box 2:48)
    - "We Are in Hot Water", 1970 Jan 15 (Box 2:49)
    - "Things You Needn't Know But You May Wish To", 1970 Apr 5 (Box 2:50)
    - "Let's Go Ice Fishing", 1970 May 11 (Box 2:51)
    - "Let's Go Ice Fishing", 1970 May 24 (Box 2:52)
    - "The Duck That Doesn't Quack", 1970 Jun 5 (Box 2:53)
    - "Connecticut", 1970 Jun 16 (Box 2:54)
    - "Nature's Untamed Shrews", 1970 Jul 26 (Box 2:55)
    - "Deerhunting in Connecticut", 1970 Sep 8 (Box 2:56)
    - "Connecticut", undated, 1970 Oct (Box 2:57)
    - "Timberdoodle Dandy", 1970 Dec 12 (Box 2:58)
    - "Fly Rodding with Poppers", undated, 1970 (Box 2:59)
    - "Ice-Fishing in Connecticut", undated, 1970 (Box 2:60)
    - "Valiant Wild Goose", undated, 1970 (Box 2:61)
    - "Connecticut", ca. 1970-1971 (Box 2:62)
    - "Rhode Island", 1971 Jan 24 (Box 2:63)
    - "Space Age Fish Hatchery", 1971 Feb 18 (Box 2:64)
    - "Northeast Reports", 1971 Feb 27 (Box 2:65)
    - "Our Wildest Drummer", 1971 Mar 30 (Box 2:66)
    - "Connecticut Woodcock", 1`971 Mar (Box 2:66-1)
    - Squet Fishing, 1971 Apr 20 (Box 2:67)
    - "Whimsical Is the Woodstock", 1971 MAy 10 (Box 2:68)
    - "The Fox Who Thinks He's a Cat", 1971 May 12 (Box 2:69)
    - "Nature's Happiest Playboy", 1971 May 15 (Box 2:70)
    - "Surfmen Never Sleep", 1971 Oct 12 (Box 3:71)
    - Connecticut/Rhode Island, 1971 Oct 14 (Box 3:72)
    - "Maine's Shirt-Sleeve Codding", 1971 Oct 22 (Box 3:73)
    - "Connecticut", 1971 Dec 27 (Box 3:74)
    - "Wild Wahoo," Salt Water Fisherman, 1971 Dec (Box 3:75)
    - Rhode Island, 1972 Jan 13 (Box 3:76)
    - "The Saga of Whitey Mouse, 1972 Mar 10 (Box 3:77)
    - "Poor Man's Lobster", 1972 Mar 12 (Box 3:78)
    - Salt-Water Fishing, Connecticut and Rhode Island Shores, 1972 Mar 28 (Box 3:79)
    - "Virginia's Red Gladiators", 1972 Jul 29 (Box 3:80)
    - "Rhode Island", 1972 Oct 1 (Box 3:81)
    - "Connecticut Foxhunting", 1972 Oct 26 (Box 3:82)
    - "Whitey Mouse", 1972 Nov 18 (Box 3:83)
    - Foreign Trawlers, 1972 Nov 26 (Box 3:84)
    - "Silver from the Sea", 1972 Nov 29 (Box 3:85)
    - "Connecticut Camping", 1972 Nov 30 (Box 3:86)
    - "Gray Ghost of the Groves", 1972 Dec 8 (Box 3:87)
    - "Our Cutest Playboy", 1973 Jan 3 (Box 3:88)
    - "The Porcupine Has His Points", 1973 Jan 17 (Box 3:89)
    - "The Live-Line Mystique", 1973 Jan 29 (Box 3:90)
    - "Everybody's After His Skin", 1973 Feb 20 (Box 3:91)
    - "Connecticut", 1973 Mar 3 (Box 3:92)
    - "Carolina's Winter Blues", 1973 Mar 11 (Box 3:93)
    - "Everybody's After His Skin", 1973 Mar 15 (Box 3:94)
    - "Dixie's Red Sluggers", 1973 Mar 23 (Box 3:95)
    - "Tom Thumb Tough Guy", 1973 Apr 10 (Box 3:96)
    - "Rhode Island's Squeteague", 1973 Apr 27 (Box 3:97)
    - "King Cottontail: The Bounding Bunny",, 1973 May 10 (Box 3:98)
    - "Fishing at Hatchery Begins June 1," New Haven Register, 1973 May 16 (Box 3:99)
    - "Yankeeland's Salty Trout", 1973 Jun 21 (Box 3:100)
    - "Bottom Bounty", 1973 Jul 5 (Box 3:101)
    - "Connecticut Deer Hunting, 1973 Aug 17 (Box 3:102)
    - "Rhody's Frostbite Mackerel", 1973 Aug 17 (Box 3:103)
    - "A Passion for Porgies", 1973 Aug 19 (Box 3:104)
    - "Fishing with an Octopus", 1973 Sep 6 (Box 3:105)
    - "Fishing with an Octopus", 1973 Oct 22 (Box 3:106)
    - "Whimsical Is the Woodcock," Ford Times, 1973 Oct (Box 3:107)
    - "A Pilgrim at Galilee", 1973 Dec 13 (Box 3:108)
    - "Connecticut Fishing R/V", ca. 1973 (Box 3:109)
    - "Rhode Island Fishing", ca. 1973 (Box 3:110)
    - "The Saga of Yellowleg", 1974 Jan 7 (Box 3:111)
    - "Trout with the Light Touch", 1974 Jan 15 (Box 3:112)
    - "Who's a Dumb Bunny?", 1974 Jan 24 (Box 3:113)
    - "Auf Wiedersehen, Little Walden", 1974 Apr 23 (Box 3:114)
    - "Nature's Tree Planter", 1974 Sep 16 (Box 3:115)
    - "Connecticut Shad Fishing", 1974 Dec (Box 3:116)
    - "How to Catch Bluefish Two and Three at a Time," True's Fishing Yearbook, 25th Edition, 1974 (Box 3:117)
    - Connecticut, 1975 Jan 11 (Box 3:118)
    - "The Porcupine Has His Points", 1975 Jan 22 (Box 3:119)
    - "Weather Prophet without Honor", 1975 Feb 19 (Box 3:120)
    - "Try Yellow Perch", 1975 Feb (Box 3:121)
    - "An Old Man Told Me", 1975 Mar 26 (Box 3:122)
    - Connecticut/Rhode Island, 1975 Apr 8 (Box 3:123)
    - "Torpedo with Teeth", 1975 Apr 22 (Box 3:124)
    - "Mackerel Magic in New Hampshire", 1975 May 19 (Box 3:125)
    - "Burglar in the Treetops", 1975 Sep 17 (Box 3:126)
    - "Samson of the Surf", 1975 Oct 8 (Box 3:127)
    - "Weather Prophet without Honor", 1975 Oct 18 (Box 3:128)
    - "The Porcupine Has His Points", 1975 Oct 30 (Box 4:129)
    - "Bandit of the Brushlands", undated, 1975 (Box 4:130)
    - "Blue Invaders", ca. 1975 (Box 4:131)
    - "The Fun Fish", ca. 1975 (Box 4:132)
    - "Live-Lining for Stripers", ca. 1975 (Box 4:133)
    - Untitled, ca. 1975 (Box 4:134)
    - "White Perch Come First", ca. 1975 (Box 4:135)
    - "Wild Man of the Weeds", ca. 1975 (Box 4:136)
    - "Bandit of the Brushlands", 1976 Jan (Box 4:137)
    - "Nature's Toothiest Engineer," Ford Times, 1976 Mar (Box 4:138)
    - "Our Fightin'est Featherweight", 1976 Apr 30 (Box 4:139)
    - "The Comeback of Mr. Gorgeous", 1976 Sep 8 (Box 4:140)
    - "Kokaneeland", 1976 Oct 2 (Box 4:141)
    - "Everybody's After His Skin", 1976 Oct 27 (Box 4:142)
    - "Wilderness Houdini", 1976 Nov 12 (Box 4:143)
    - "The Elusive Cottontail," Ford Times, 1976 Nov (Box 4:144)
    - "Forty-Four Feet a Second", 1977 Feb 18 (Box 4:145)
    - "Family Man", 1977 May 10 (Box 4:146)
    - "Poor Man's Pig", 1977 May 18 (Box 4:147)
    - "Our Smallest Pig", 1977 May 23 (Box 4:148)
    - "Our Friend Newt," Ford Times, 1977 May (Box 4:149)
    - "Nature's Glamor Boy", 1977 Jul 20 (Box 4:150)
    - "Tales of the Whitetail", 1977 Sep 22 (Box 4:151)
    - "Terror of the Treetops", 1977 Nov 1 (Box 4:152)
    - "COUGAR!", 1977 Dec 16 (Box 4:153)
    - "Wily Tactician of the Brushlands," Ford Times, 1978 Jan (Box 4:154)
    - "Salt Water Pike", 1978 Jun 2 (Box 4:155)
    - "It's No Disgrace to Be a Rat", 1978 Apr 11 (Box 4:156)
    - "Fiercest Fighter in the Field," Ford Times, 1978 Aug (Box 4:157)
    - "The Blue Hellions", undated, 1978 (Box 4:158)
    - "2,002 Miles of Striped Bass", 1979 Jan 15 (Box 4:159)
    - "King of Game Birds", 1979 Jan 22 (Box 4:160)
    - "Our Friend Newt", 1979 Feb 9 (Box 4:161)
    - "Feathered Dive-Bomber", 1979 Apr 25 (Box 4:162)
    - "The Indian Summer Fish", 1979 Nov (Box 4:163)
    - "How I Caught the Trouts," Sports Afield, 1980 Apr (Box 4:164)
    - "How Sly Is Mr. Red?", 1980 Jun 6 (Box 4:165)
    - "Buffoon of the Brushlands", 1981 Jan 15 (Box 4:166)
    - "Nature's Glamor Boy", 1981 Mar 24 (Box 4:167)
    - "The Animal That Shoots Back," Sports Afield, 1981 Apr (Box 4:168)
    - "The Animal That Can Shoot Back", ca. 1981 Apr (Box 4:169)
    - "Pokey the Possum", 1981 May 1 (Box 4:170)
    - "The Knight of Many Spears," Sports Afield, 1981 Oct (Box 4:171)
    - "Woodland Wizards," Sports Afield, 1982 Mar (Box 4:172)
    - "Leave It to the Beaver," Sports Afield, 1982 Apr (Box 4:173)
  - Subseries B: Undated Articles and Manuscripts, undated
    - "Acrobat in Fur", undated (Box 5:174)
    - "The Amberjack's Western Cousin", undated (Box 5:175)
    - "Armored Warrior of the Sought", undated (Box 5:176)
    - "Atlantic Mackerel", undated (Box 5:177)
    - "Ballerinas of the Blue" (Box 5:178)
    - "Bandit in Black Feathers" (Box 5:179)
    - "Battling the Boston Blues" (Box 5:180)
    - "Best Bets for Vacation Fishing" (Box 5:181)
    - "Blue Bombers" (Box 5:182)
    - "Bluefish: Quest for the Blue Hellions", undated (Box 5:183)
    - "The Bobcat: Bandit of the Brushlands" (published), undated (Box 5:184)
    - "Bombshell of the Brushlands", undated (Box 5:185)
    - "Broadbill Swordfish", undated (Box 5:186)
    - "Bunker-Dunking for Bass", undated (Box 5:188)
    - "The Canniest Brownie That Swims", undated (Box 5:189)
    - "Channel Bass: Half Torpedo, Half Bulldozer" (2 copies), undated (Box 5:190)
    - "Chips of the Old Chopping Block", undated (Box 5:191)
    - "Connecticut", undated (Box 5:192)
    - "Connecticut", undated (Box 5:193)
    - "Connecticut River Variety", undated (Box 5:194)
    - "Connecticut Smelting", undated (Box 5:195)
    - "Connecticut Woodcock", undated (Box 5:196)
    - "Connecticut's New Sport-Kokanee Salmon", undated (Box 5:197)
    - "Connecticut's Salty Trout", undated (Box 5:198)
    - "Cranky Is the Crow," Reader's Digest, undated (Box 5:199)
    - "Conning the Crappies", undated (Box 5:200)
    - "The Deadly Live-Line", undated (Box 5:201)
    - "The Dean of Nature's Engineers", undated (Box 5:202)
    - "A Doll Told Me", undated (Box 5:203)
    - "Dumb Bunnies Aren't So Dumb", undated (Box 5:204)
    - "The East's Mystery Fish", undated (Box 5:205)
    - "Everybody's After His Skin", undated (Box 5:206)
    - "Family Man", undated (Box 5:207)
    - "A Fighting Little Guy", undated (Box 5:208)
    - "The Fish You Hunt", undated (Box 5:209)
    - "The Fish Who Is a Fisherman", undated (Box 5:210)
    - "Flying Carpets in Fins", undated (Box 5:211)
    - "Forty-Four Feet a Second", undated (Box 5:212)
    - "Forty-Four Feet a Second", undated (Box 5:213)
    - "Fox in Fins", undated (Box 5:214)
    - "Hook and Bullet", undated (Box 5:215)
    - "Housatonic Hazards", undated (Box 5:216)
    - "How to Catch Fillet of Sole", undated (Box 5:217)
    - "I Catch Salmon with Maggots", undated (Box 5:218)
    - "Live-Lining for Stripers", undated (Box 5:219)
    - "Mackerel by the Millions", undated (Box 5:220)
    - "Mackerel Magic", undated (Box 5:221)
    - "Master of Chemical Warfare", undated (Box 5:224)
    - "Mighty Midget of Mining", undated (Box 5:225)
    - "Mighty Swordman of the Sea", undated (Box 5:226)
    - "Nature's Cutest Playboy", undated (Box 5:227)
    - "Nature's Featherweight Champion", undated (Box 5:228)
    - "Nature's Own Engineer", undated (Box 5:229)
    - "Nature's Senior Engineer", undated (Box 5:230)
    - "Next Door to Davy Jones" (published), undated (Box 5:231)
    - "Nimble Is the Deer", undated (Box 6:232)
    - "No Sport for Hippies", undated (Box 6:233)
    - "The Ocean's Supermackerel", undated (Box 6:234)
    - "Our Fight'est Featherweight", undated (Box 6:235)
    - "Our Silent Friends the Clams", undated (Box 6:236)
    - "Our Wildest Drummer", undated (Box 6:237)
    - "Our Wildest Drummer", undated (Box 6:238)
    - "Please Pass the Ants", undated (Box 6:239)
    - "Pole Vaulter of the Sea", undated (Box 6:240)
    - "Quest for the Blue Hellions", undated (Box 6:241)
    - "Red Reynard's Shy Cousin", undated (Box 6:242)
    - "Rhode Island Fishing", undated (Box 6:243)
    - "Savage, Surly, Slashing: SNOOK!", undated (Box 6:244)
    - "Silver from the Sea", undated (Box 6:245)
    - "Silver King of the Mackerels", undated (Box 6:246)
    - "South with the Summer," #1, undated (Box 6:247)
    - "South with the Summer," #2, undated (Box 6:248)
    - "Spinning Goes Nautical" (published), undated (Box 6:249)
    - "Striped Bass: No Sport for Sissies", undated (Box 6:250)
    - "Summer Fishing in Rhode Island", undated (Box 6:251)
    - "Surfcraft for Rocky Shores", undated (Box 6:252)